<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My path to enlightnment]]></title>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-13T10:35:42+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://luisalima.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luisa Lima]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silencing nagging logs in rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/disabling-nagging-logs-in-rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T10:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/disabling-nagging-logs-in-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, I was trying to do some meaningful debugging in rails with</p>

<pre><code>
    logger.debug
</pre>


<p></code></p>

<p>and I was being particularly nagged by these annoying messages from Webrick:</p>

<pre><code>
    WARN Could not determine content-length of response body. Set content-length of the response or set Response#chunked = true [closed]
</pre>


<p></code></p>

<p>The way to solve this? I am using &#8216;thin&#8217; instead of Webrick as a development server (yeah, I know that there are <a href="https://bugs.ruby-lang.org/attachments/2300/204_304_keep_alive.patch">patches to solve this in Webrick</a> but I decided to go a bit aggressive instead).</p>

<p>And another thing that nagged me were the asset pipeline messages with the gets for the css, js, images, etc. So one way to shut Sprockets up is given <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/6312448/how-to-disable-logging-of-asset-pipeline-sprockets-messages-in-rails-3-1">here</a>, and just for the record:</p>

<pre><code>
    # place this code in config/initializers/quiet_assets.rb
    if Rails.env.development?
  Rails.application.assets.logger = Logger.new('/dev/null')
  Rails::Rack::Logger.class_eval do
    def call_with_quiet_assets(env)
      previous_level = Rails.logger.level
      Rails.logger.level = Logger::ERROR if env['PATH_INFO'] =~ %r{^/assets/}
      call_without_quiet_assets(env)
    ensure
      Rails.logger.level = previous_level
    end
    alias_method_chain :call, :quiet_assets
  end
end
</pre>


<p></code></p>

<p>Ahhhhh now I can actually see <strong>meaningful</strong> logs in my development log. <em>whew!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Octopress blog...]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T09:56:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I created this blog specifically to jot down notes of interesting / useful / meaningful stuff I find during my adventures with development, which I hope are useful to others.</p>

<p>And to start with, here is a link to a post that really helped me out <a href="http://code.dblock.org/Octopress-setting-up-a-blog-and-contributing-to-an-existing-one">Octopress: Setting up a Blog and Contributing to an Existing One</a>. It wasn&#8217;t really clear to me from Octopress instructions that I had to run rake generate and rake deploy; I was just trying to make the git commits and push by hand (and becoming really frustrated by it). So, just for my own reference:</p>

<pre><code> # do stuff in your blog, like rake new_post
    # then generate the blog
    rake generate
    # then save the source branch and push it to Github
    git add .
    git commit -m "whatever message"
    git push origin source
    # and now, this is where the magic happens! this takes care
    # of pushing everything automagically onto the master branch!
    rake deploy
</code></pre>


<p>(depending on your system, you might need to run bundle exec followed by the rake commands).</p>

<p>Oh, and also&#8230; to delete a post, delete it only from <pre><code>blog-root/source/_posts/post-title</code></pre> and then run the commands above again. The rake tasks from Octopress take care of everything.</p>

<p>This cool minimalistic theme is from <a href="http://zespia.tw">zespia.tw</a>, and it&#8217;s called <a href="http://zespia.tw/Octopress-Theme-Slash/">Slash</a>.</p>

<p>Ta-da!</p>

<p>So far I&#8217;m really enjoying Octopress &#8211; I chose it because I want to be able to do everything from the shell, and never leave my dev environment and my beloved ST2/emacs combination.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
