<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rspec | Entreprevelopment adventures]]></title>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/categories/rspec/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T16:02:42+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://luisalima.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luisa Lima]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I test part IV -- testing controllers in rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/09/how-i-test-part-iv/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T11:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/09/how-i-test-part-iv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First and foremost, I advise you to <a href="http://everydayrails.com/2012/04/07/testing-series-rspec-controllers.html">read this post from Everyday Rails</a>. It gives a very nice overview, by controller method, of what controller tests should look like. Like Aaron, I had read about testing and noone advises you to test controllers -- rather, they would say "test models and do integration testing, and controllers will be covered by those tests". But as you can see in <a href="http://solnic.eu/2012/02/02/yes-you-should-write-controller-tests.html">"Yes, you should write controller tests!"</a>, controllers should be tested. I'll post their reasons here and add a few reasons extra why to test controllers:</p>

<ul>
<li>Controllers are models, too;</li>
<li>Controller specs can be written and ran more quickly than integration tests;</li>
<li>(My own reason #1) It's very easy to write them using the basic scaffholding provided;</li>
<li>(My own reason #2) If they are not easy to write, it's because you are doing some nasty complex not-that-CRUDdy stuff. Uh oh. Which is what was happening in my case.</li>
</ul>


<p>But mainly, I don't see tests as testing instruments per se. I see tests as a way to reflect on your code, see how complex it is, and an opportunity for refactoring as well.</p>

<p>That being said... What I did was to pick up the scaffholding and adapt it as needed, and here is the trouble that I ran into when testing controllers.</p>

<p>First, run the scaffholding routing tests. Yeah, just go ahead and do it. And now correct them to account for all the nested resource paths that you have, as well as the paths that you don't want to allow. You are going to need it.</p>

<p>Now open your scaffholding controller tests. Each example refers to a single method of the controller, and you have tests for each action that the method must take. If you run them and they don't behave as expected, there can be several reasons, but from my (very limited experience), here are the most common:</p>

<ol>
<li>you didn't set your valid_attributes properly -- including having nested attributes that are required and are not being set;</li>
<li>you are using authentication and need a current_user (modifying valid_session);</li>
<li>you have nested resources and so need to set the id(s) of the parent resource(s).</li>
</ol>


<p>Let's go through each of these in order...</p>

<h2>Attributes</h2>

<p>First and foremost, have you tested your factories in your models? Good.</p>

<p>What I usually do is to make use of the <em>FactoryGirl attributes_for</em> method and just stick it in valid_attributes:</p>

<pre><code>def valid_attributes
  FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:my_model)
end
</code></pre>


<p>However, this won't work when you have <em>validates_presence_of</em> for a has_one association. Say that my model has:</p>

<pre><code>
    has_one :banana
    validates_presence_of :banana
    accepts_nested_attributes_for :banana
</code></pre>


<p>Then, even if you have the association with the banana model in your "my_model" Factory, you'll get an error because attributes_for does not include associations and thus banana is not there. To fix that, we do:</p>

<pre><code>def valid_attributes
    banana_attribs = FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:banana)
  FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:my_model).merge({:banana_attributes => banana_attribs})
end
</code></pre>


<p>Finally... if your model belongs_to another model, let's say that it looks like this (can you tell I'm hungry?):</p>

<pre><code>
    has_one :banana
    validates_presence_of :banana
    accepts_nested_attributes_for :banana
    belongs_to :strawberry
</code></pre>


<p>Assuming that you set up this association correctly in FactoryGirl, you'll have a strawberry_id in your model's attributes. You have two options: either to set it up as an attr_accessible, or to get rid of it in the valid_attributes in order not to get a security error:</p>

<pre><code>def valid_attributes
    banana_attribs = FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:banana)
  FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:my_model).except(:strawberry_id).merge({:banana_attributes => banana_attribs})
end
</code></pre>


<p>Disclaimer: I was going to write a method go go through all the associations and do this automagically, but then I figured that it was kind of cheating because it is really valuable, like I said, to reflect on the way that you are writing your code. At least for me, it is.</p>

<h2>Authentication and authorization -- you need valid session data and a current_user variable</h2>

<p>If you are using any kind of authentication, you need to set up a valid current user and a valid session. Here's <a href="https://github.com/plataformatec/devise/wiki/How-To%3a-Controllers-and-Views-tests-with-Rails-3-%28and-rspec%29">how to do it if you are using Devise</a>:</p>

<pre><code>before(:each) do
  @request.env["devise.mapping"] = Devise.mappings[:user]
  user = FactoryGirl.create(:user)
  user.add_role(:master_of_all_fruits) # don't forget that if you are doing authorization, you need to set up the correct role as well
    user.confirm! # or set a confirmed_at inside the factory. Only necessary if you are using the confirmable module
  sign_in user
end

it "should have a current_user" do
  subject.current_user.should_not be_nil
end
</code></pre>


<p>Also, don't forget to set up the session:</p>

<pre><code>def valid_session
  {"warden.user.user.key" => session["warden.user.user.key"]}
end
</code></pre>


<p>The errors that are given are not clear at all in this case, so make sure to check that you didn't forget to set up the valid session and the current_user!</p>

<h2>Nested resources</h2>

<p>If my_model is a nested resource, you need to adapt your controller spec in order to account for that. Suppose that we have</p>

<pre><code>resources :strawberries do
  resources :my_model do
</code></pre>


<p>When you run the scaffholding for my_model controller tests, you'll get a "No route matches..." followed by a hash of my_model.</p>

<p>So what you have to do is to:
* add the strawberry_id to the actions that require a /strawberries/:strawberry_id/my_model route;
* add the @strawberry to the redirects that require the same type of routes.</p>

<p>What I do is to use a before(:each) that creates the required @strawberry:</p>

<pre><code>before(:each) do
    @strawberry = FactoryGirl.create(:strawberry)
  end

it "redirects to the created my_model" do
post :create, {:strawberry_id => @strawberry.id, :my_model => valid_attributes}, valid_session
response.should redirect_to([@strawberry, MyModel.last])
end

it "redirects to the my_models list" do
  my_model = MyModel.create! valid_attributes
  delete :destroy, {:strawberry_id => @strawberry.id, :id => my_model.to_param}, valid_session
  response.should redirect_to(strawberry_my_models_url(@strawberry))
end

# Don't forget to create my_models for @strawberry in the nested route!
describe "GET index" do
  it "assigns all my_models as @my_models" do
    my_model = MyModel.create! valid_attributes
    @strawberry.my_models << my_model
    get :index, {:strawberry_id => @strawberry.id}, valid_session
    assigns(:my_models).should eq([my_model])
  end
end
</code></pre>


<p>What if you also have a route like this:</p>

<pre><code> resources :my_models, :only => [:index, :show]
</code></pre>


<p>What I do is that I divide the tests into two contexts:</p>

<pre><code> context "directly via /my_models" do
  #...
end

context "via /strawberries/:strawberry_id/my_models" do
  #...
end
</code></pre>


<p>and place the "before(:each)" that creates @strawberry in the nested route context.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I managed to detect many bugs in my controllers doing this (especially variables that I had assumed not to be nil and that were not set). Testing controllers is easy and fast, so I strongly advise you to test your controllers!</p>

<p>Eventually, I'll also do a post on integration testing with rspec, but for now, <a href="http://everydayrails.com/2012/04/24/testing-series-rspec-requests.html">here's another resource from Everyday Rails that covers the topic very nicely</a>. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random notes on Factory Girl Part II]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/random-notes-on-factory-girl-part-ii/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T20:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/random-notes-on-factory-girl-part-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>More random/tutorialish aspects of my usage of the FactoryGirl gem. I do advise you to read their <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md#associations">getting started guide</a>, it helps a lot. This is more of a reference of the things I found most useful. If you have any questions/corrections/observations, let me know in the comments.</p>

<h2>FactoryGirl and Polymorphic named associations</h2>

<p>If you have polymorphic associations with different names, here's how to go about it in factories:</p>

<pre><code> factory :category, aliases: [:category_one, :category_two] </code></pre>


<p>There are other approaches to this problem <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7747945/factorygirl-and-polymorphic-associations">here</a>, but I find this one to be the simplest and so far it hasn't gotten me into trouble (perhaps yet :-) ).</p>

<h2>Attributes_for</h2>

<p>This is probably very obvious, but I find it useful to use attributes_for from FactoryGirl to build the valid attributes for use in controller specs.</p>

<pre><code> def valid_attributes
    FactoryGirl.attributes_for(:my_model)
    end
</code></pre>


<p>One thing that is useful to know is that attributes_for ignores associations, and thus does not include attributes that are related to associations even if you have an association in the factory. <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10290286/factorygirl-why-does-attributes-for-omit-some-attributes">Here is a post at stackoverflow</a> that provides you with the foreign keys in the attributes if you need them.</p>

<h2>Has_and_belongs_to_many associations</h2>

<p>I'm just adding this for my own reference. It's in the <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/wiki/Usage">FactoryGirl getting started wiki</a>.</p>

<pre><code> FactoryGirl.define do
  factory :person do
    first_name { 'James' }
    books {
      Array(5..10).sample.times.map do
        FactoryGirl.create(:book) # optionally add traits: FactoryGirl.create(:book, :book_description)
      end
    }
  end
end
</code></pre>


<p>There is more in FactoryGirl associations <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md#associations">here</a>.</p>

<h2>DRYing up: Traits</h2>

<p>I just discovered traits, which are ways to add state to a factory (read: create factories whose attributes have different values without having to go through aliases). I am <a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/23673635798/remove-duplication-with-factorygirls-traits">shamelessly copying Thoughtbot's example</a> because I think it's the clearest one to have here for your reference:</p>

<pre><code> FactoryGirl.define do
  factory :todo_item do
    name 'Pick up a gallon of milk'

    trait :completed do
      complete true
    end

    trait :not_completed do
      complete false
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>


<h2>DRYing up: inheritance</h2>

<p>Something that I wasn't making much use of -- you can nest factories, which allows you to create multiple factories for the same class without repeating common attributes:</p>

<pre><code>
factory :user do
    name "testing"

  factory :super_user do
    super_powers true
  end
end
</code></pre>


<h2>Tracking factories</h2>

<p>I followed the advice <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md#activesupport-instrumentation">here</a> to track factories. I think it's useful to know how factories are being used.</p>

<h2>If you want to go really in depth...</h2>

<p>You have a <a href="http://www.arailsdemo.com/posts/39">very nice post on code reading of the factorygirl gem here</a>. You can even learn something about how to do cool stuff in ruby/rails like:</p>

<pre><code> def set(attribute, value)
    @instance.send(:"#{attribute}=", value)
  end
</code></pre>


<p>And that's all, folks (for now...)!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random pseudo-tutorialish notes on Factory Girl, part I]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/random-notes-on-factory-girl/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T18:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/random-notes-on-factory-girl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The guys at Thoughtbot do an excellent job. I especially love shoulda and high_voltage. I have a love/hate relationship with factory_girl, so I decided to write this post trying to detail some of the ways I've been using it. Maybe it will help someone. Hope it does!</p>

<p>First of all, what is a factory and what do you need it for? Factories are a (healthier) alternative to fixtures, and fixtures are simply a "fixed state" for models, used as baseline for tests. In Rails, fixtures get automatically loaded into the test database before tests are run, and you define them in a YAML file. However, they can become awkward pretty easily, so Factories were created -- frameworks designed to allow a quick creation of fully featured objects for testing.</p>

<p>And now you ask, why don't we just create the object directly before each test? Think required attributes and associations -- if your model has 10 attributes and 5 different associations you might want to have somewhere where you can create valid instances of that model upfront and then reuse them.</p>

<p>So, we have (somewhat) established what factories are for. <a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2012-07-14-why-i-don-t-like-factory_girl">Just beware of the downsides of using factories</a> (quoting the blog in the link, which is highly recommended):
"A big feature of tests is to give you feedback on your code. Tests and code have a symbiotic relationship. Your tests inform your code. If a test is complicated, your code is complicated. Ultimately, because tests are a client of your code, you can see how easy or hard your code's interfaces are."</p>

<p>Yup, I feel your pain, bro. My latest project has tons of models, polymorphic interfaces, STI's, etc. Ultimately, flexibility creates complexity, and it's better to avoid extra features to keep simplicity. But I digress.</p>

<p>So, how do we use these lil' bastards? :-)</p>

<h2>Configuration</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md">Getting started</a> guide provides what you need. Except... I don't think it's that clear that if you are using Rspec, those lines</p>

<pre><code>
    require 'factory_girl'
    FactoryGirl.find_definitions
</code></pre>


<p>go in the spec_helper.rb file. More precisely, <em>FactoryGirl.find_definitions</em> goes inside the <em>RSpec.configure do |config|</em> block.</p>

<p><em>But:</em> if you are using Spork, you need to reload Factory definitions at each run, otherwise you get a "factory not registered" error. So, place the following inside the <em>Spork.each_run do</em> block:</p>

<pre><code>
    Spork.each_run do
    # ....
        FactoryGirl.definition_file_paths << File.join(File.dirname(__FILE__), 'factories')
      FactoryGirl.find_definitions
    # etc...
</code></pre>


<p>There you go! Everything nicely configured :-) Also, you can use FactoryGirl in rails console! Just use the code <a href="http://blog.thefrontiergroup.com.au/2011/03/reloading-factory-girl-factories-in-the-rails-3-console/">in this post</a>, which I'll shamelessly copy here for posterity and for my own reference:</p>

<pre><code>
    ActionDispatch::Callbacks.after do
      # Reload the factories
      return unless (Rails.env.development? || Rails.env.test?)

      unless FactoryGirl.factories.blank? # first init will load factories, this should only run on subsequent reloads
        FactoryGirl.factories.clear
        FactoryGirl.find_definitions
      end
    end
</code></pre>


<p>You can also just run this code directly in the console. If you do have sequences defined, you'll need to add the following extra:</p>

<pre><code>
FactoryGirl.factories.clear
FactoryGirl.sequences.clear
FactoryGirl.find_definitions
</code></pre>


<p>(and if you are using <a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/23673635798/remove-duplication-with-factorygirls-traits">traits</a>, apparently you need to add FactoryGirl.traits.clear as well).</p>

<h2>In unit testing</h2>

<p>So first things first... You can have a file for testing factories but I'd rather have the test for the validity of the factory in the model test file itself -- this to avoid incurring errors when you are focusing on testing a particular model, all because your factory was ill-defined. So go ahead and test the factory itself:</p>

<pre><code>
    it "has a valid factory" do
        m = FactoryGirl.build(:my_model)
        m.should be_valid
    end
</code></pre>


<p>What do we do if this goes wrong and we can't sort out the error? Go to the console, write</p>

<pre><code>
m = FactoryGirl.build(:my_model)
m.valid?  # duh, it'll be false
m.save    # just to trigger all validations callbacks etc that we might have
m.errors
</code></pre>


<p>And now go ahead and complete your factory with the necessary information. Simple enough, right? The syntax for defining factories is explained pretty well <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md">in the starting guide</a> so I won't go to the trouble, except for the case when we are using Faker.</p>

<h2>With Faker</h2>

<p>Faker is a cool gem for... you guessed it, generating fake data. And here's how you do it:</p>

<pre><code>
  factory :company do
    name { Faker::Company.name }
    phone {Faker::PhoneNumber.cell_phone}
  end
</code></pre>


<p>Yup, just a normal block, not too bad.</p>

<h2>Sequences</h2>

<p>Sequences are used for attributes that must be unique, such as email addresses. You can define sequences "outside" of the factory definition, or inside as a block:</p>

<pre><code>
  sequence :email do |n|
    "test#{n}@example.com"
  end

    factory :user do
        email
    password "password"
    password_confirmation "password"
    phone {Faker::PhoneNumber.cell_phone}
    end
</code></pre>


<p>is the same as:</p>

<pre><code>
    factory :user do
        sequence(:email) { |n| "test#{n}@example.com"}
    password "password"
    password_confirmation "password"
    phone {Faker::PhoneNumber.cell_phone}
    end
</code></pre>


<h2>Associations</h2>

<p>Associations in factories are simply created by adding the factory name for the association in the other factory block. For example, if my user has_one location:</p>

<pre><code>
    factory :user do
        sequence(:email) { |n| "test#{n}@example.com"}
    password "password"
    password_confirmation "password"
    phone {Faker::PhoneNumber.cell_phone}
    location   # ta-da!
    end
</code></pre>


<p>More detail about associations with FactoryGirl <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl/blob/master/GETTING_STARTED.md#associations">here</a>.</p>

<p>More about this tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I test part III: Why rspec?]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/how-i-test-part-iii/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T16:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/how-i-test-part-iii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why RSpec? That is a good question. My main reason for using RSpec right now is because I want to have a testing + documentation + TODO bundle, all in one, like a shampoo:</p>

<ul>
<li>testing -- ok, RSpec does make things a tad more complicated for testing. I believe that testing actually makes you learn more about what you code, and RSpec, being a DSL, can make things esoteric enough that sometimes you don't know exactly what you're testing (I confess that I like Test::Unit more because it's simpler for developers to read -- assert that this gives this result). But, on the other hand, you have shoulda! :-)</li>
<li>documentation -- the exact same thing that makes testing a bit more esoteric, makes documentation a piece of cake. You want to know how something works? Just read the tests. And RSpec does make that side of testing much clearer.</li>
<li>TODO -- yup, that's right. If you have features that you want to implement later on, just add a "pending" spec with the description of what you want to do. Of course that you can do that in Test::Unit as well, but it's not as beautiful and immediate as in RSpec.</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course that I'm really just beginning and I might change my mind eventually. <a href="http://www.rubyinside.com/dhh-offended-by-rspec-debate-4610.html">Even the creator of Rails argues against RSPec</a>, and there are quite a few arguments against it (if you missed the link, here's an <a href="http://objectreload.com/articles/2010/09/thoughts-on-testing-part-1.html">excellent blog post on that</a>).</p>

<p>By the way, I'm abiding by this rule from the last post:</p>

<p>"- Keep things flat — deeply nested contexts are ugly as they hinder readability of your test cases. Split your tests up into different files if they’re getting too long."</p>

<p>I was trying to make things DRY in the tests, and then I thought... why bother, exactly? It's better if they are more readable, for the sake of documentation as stated above. Amen, brothers.</p>

<h2>Why not Cucumber for request specs?</h2>

<p>All the reasons are in this <a href="http://epimetrics.com/entries/3129">excellent post</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I test part II - testing models]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/how-i-test-part-ii/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T10:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/how-i-test-part-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Testing models</h2>

<p>From <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/testing.html">rails guides</a>:</p>

<p>"Ideally, you would like to include a test for everything which could possibly break. It’s a good practice to have at least one test for each of your validations and at least one test for every method in your model."</p>

<p>Which leads me to...</p>

<h2>Why I use shoulda</h2>

<p>I think that the best thing is just to take a peek at <a href="http://cheat.errtheblog.com/s/rspec_shoulda/">The shoulda cheat sheets</a>.</p>

<p>You actually get a guide of what to test by looking at the cheat sheet! It's too bad that it's not up to date (actually I think that the whole site is not up to date -- even the gem doesn't work anymore, which I think is too bad :-( )</p>

<p>Furthermore, it's great for lazy people and it's definitely easier on the eyes. Just check the following example:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4339197.js?file=shoulda_model.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># without shoulda... tons of code :-)
it &quot;should belong to person&quot; do
	Model.reflect_on_association(:person).macro.should == :belongs_to
end

# with shoulda... one-liner!
it{should belong_to(:person)}
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Convinced? ;-)</p>

<h2>What I test exactly with shoulda</h2>

<p>I go through the whole list of shoulda macros for models, and I just use and abuse them. Since the cheat sheet is not up to date, I created a new one (just for models for now) at:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4339490.js?file=shoulda_cheat_model.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># updated from the original @ http://cheat.errtheblog.com/s/rspec_shoulda
# just a subset -- models -- is included here. I'll update this, and create cheat sheets for others, as I go along.
# I marked the ones I added with NEW and also added the links to the corresponding code, as I think it's useful.
# Any comments/corrections are welcome!

# =================  Data and Associations =======================
# https://github.com/thoughtbot/shoulda-matchers/tree/master/lib/shoulda/matchers/active_record

it { should_not have_db_column(:admin).of_type(:boolean) }
it { should have_db_column(:salary).
      of_type(:decimal).
      with_options(:precision =&gt; 10, :scale =&gt; 2) }
it { should have_readonly_attributes(:password) }
it { should belong_to(:parent) }
it { should have_db_index(:id) } # NEW

it { should have_many(:friends) }
it { should have_many(:enemies).through(:friends) }
it { should have_many(:enemies).dependent(:destroy) }

it { should have_one(:god) }

it { should have_and_belong_to_many(:posts) }

it {should accept_nested_attributes_for(:user)} # NEW

# ================== Validation Matchers ============================
# https://github.com/thoughtbot/shoulda-matchers/tree/master/lib/shoulda/matchers/active_model

it { should validate_uniqueness_of(:keyword) }
it { should validate_uniqueness_of(:keyword).with_message(/dup/) }
it { should validate_uniqueness_of(:email).scoped_to(:name) }
it { should validate_uniqueness_of(:email).
              scoped_to(:first_name, :last_name) }
it { should validate_uniqueness_of(:keyword).case_insensitive }

it { should validate_presence_of(:name) }
it { should validate_presence_of(:name).
              with_message(/is not optional/) }

it { should validate_numericality_of(:age) }

it { should validate_format_of(:name).
              with('12345').
              with_message(/is not optional/) }
it { should validate_format_of(:name).
              not_with('12D45').
              with_message(/is not optional/) }

it { should validate_acceptance_of(:eula) }

it { should ensure_length_of(:password).
              is_at_least(6).
              is_at_most(20) }
it { should ensure_length_of(:name).
              is_at_least(3).
              with_short_message(/not long enough/) }
it { should ensure_length_of(:ssn).
              is_equal_to(9).
              with_message(/is invalid/) }

it { should ensure_inclusion_of(:age).in_range(0..100) }
it { should_not allow_mass_assignment_of(:password) }
it { should allow_mass_assignment_of(:first_name) }
it { should validate_format_of(:first_name).with(&quot;Carl&quot;) }

it { should validate_confirmation_of(:password) } # NEW</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Yes, it's a bit tedious. But (1) you make sure that you are actually testing all these details, which is extremely useful when you are constantly refactoring your code, and (2) it's not that slow with the multiple cursors of Sublime Text 2. You just need to have a scaffold.</p>

<h2>What I test without shoulda</h2>

<p>Apart from model methods, is there that much to test without shoulda? I test:</p>

<ul>
<li>Any model methods, extensively</li>
<li>Callbacks, extremely extensively</li>
<li>Some validations - but just to make sure I coded them right. See more of this perspective in <a href="http://www.christopherbloom.com/2011/07/12/testing-model-validations-in-rspec-the-short-and-sweet-way/">Testing model validations in rspec the short and sweet way</a></li>
</ul>


<p>... and for now, that's about it.</p>

<h2>Regarding generating fake data</h2>

<p>Like I mentioned before, I do use FactoryGirl extensively. Maybe that means that <a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2012-07-14-why-i-don-t-like-factory_girl">my models are complicated</a>? I don't know, but for now, I am sort of using good sense and stuff. Let's see what happens. I do use <a href="http://faker.rubyforge.org">Faker</a> as well. Come to think about it, will do a post on that eventually.</p>

<h2>Random issues in testing models</h2>

<p>When everything seems to be absolutely correct in the models and in the tests and you are still getting unexplainable errors, do restart guard. I already spent several hours messing around with the tests because guard didn't refresh the models. <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5855587/spork-is-really-great-but-how-can-i-get-it-to-refresh-validations-and-other-cod">There are automatic solutions</a>, but I didn't feel like hacking away the spork/guard configurations again... yet.</p>

<h2>Random resources</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://everydayrails.com/2012/03/19/testing-series-rspec-models-factory-girl.html">Everyday Rails: How I learned to test my Rails applications, Part 3: Model specs</a> - this has a very nice overview of the actual steps required to test models. Now I just cheat using shoulda, but it's very nice and useful to get a</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.christopherbloom.com/2011/07/12/testing-model-validations-in-rspec-the-short-and-sweet-way/">Testing model validations in rspec the short and sweet way</a> - it's a bit outdated, but describes how to test validations in a short way.</p></li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>Again, as I already mentioned, I am a beginner to rails and, consequently, in testing rails, so I might be doing/saying terribly wrong things. Any input is very much appreciated :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
