<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | Entreprevelopment adventures]]></title>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T20:26:18+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://luisalima.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luisa Lima]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Octopress blog...]]></title>
    <link href="http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T09:56:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://luisalima.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I created this blog specifically to jot down notes of interesting / useful / meaningful stuff I find during my adventures with development, which I hope are useful to others.</p>

<p>And to start with, here is a link to a post that really helped me out <a href="http://code.dblock.org/Octopress-setting-up-a-blog-and-contributing-to-an-existing-one">Octopress: Setting up a Blog and Contributing to an Existing One</a>. It wasn't really clear to me from Octopress instructions that I had to run rake generate and rake deploy; I was just trying to make the git commits and push by hand (and becoming really frustrated by it). So, just for my own reference:</p>

<pre><code> # do stuff in your blog, like rake new_post
    # then generate the blog
    rake generate
    # then save the source branch and push it to Github
    git add .
    git commit -m "whatever message"
    git push origin source
    # and now, this is where the magic happens! this takes care
    # of pushing everything automagically onto the master branch!
    rake deploy
</code></pre>


<p>(depending on your system, you might need to run bundle exec followed by the rake commands).</p>

<p>Oh, and also... to delete a post, delete it only from <pre><code>blog-root/source/_posts/post-title</code></pre> and then run the commands above again. The rake tasks from Octopress take care of everything.</p>

<p>This cool minimalistic theme is from <a href="http://zespia.tw">zespia.tw</a>, and it's called <a href="http://zespia.tw/Octopress-Theme-Slash/">Slash</a>.</p>

<p>Ta-da!</p>

<p>So far I'm really enjoying Octopress -- I chose it because I want to be able to do everything from the shell, and never leave my dev environment and my beloved ST2/emacs combination.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
